<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Rachael Gibson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Rachael Gibson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:38:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Picture of Transparency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/a-picture-of-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:38:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/a-picture-of-transparency/</guid>
      <description>Rachael Gibson&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;A Picture of Transparency&amp;#39;, recorded by Riot Ensemble&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3yW8vkSuoDc?si=92kAePioVE8Ji25i&#xA;Rachael during her visit to Professor Rachel Williams&amp;rsquo; lab in 2020&#xA;I recently had the opportunity to take part in the RNCM and University of Liverpool’s collaborative interdisciplinary project PRiSM 8 cubed, where 8 scientists worked with 8 composers to create new pieces inspired by scientific research. I was partnered with Professor Rachel Williams, who is a researcher in Ophthalmic Bioengineering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feedback Piano</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/feedback-piano/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:33:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/feedback-piano/</guid>
      <description>Password to watch the above Feedback Piano video: RGibson96&#xA;https://player.vimeo.com/video/428082627?h=a20e7d970e&amp;amp;amp;dnt=1&amp;amp;amp;app_id=122963&#xA;In this project, I wanted to explore how I could use interactive music systems and feedback to encourage conscious musical decision making from audiences and interactors in an installation. This is in response to how installations that feature audience interaction typically use the audience members as controllers, catalysts or performers, but audiences rarely have the opportunity to contribute their own ideas within a sound installation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destroy My Heartstrings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/destroy-my-heartstrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:22:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/destroy-my-heartstrings/</guid>
      <description>As a guitarist, I am interested in exploring ways of presenting sonically ideas surrounding gender and the electric guitar. Guitar and gender have been widely discussed in pop culture as well as academia, with both addressing similar questions of why there aren’t more female guitarists becoming as commercially successful as their male counterparts and how our relationship to the instrument differs in comparison to men.&#xA;For inspiration I decided to seek out music by female guitar players that didn’t conform to conventional ‘guitar music’ used in folk, blues, indie rock or metal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL / EXTERNAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/internal-external/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:16:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/internal-external/</guid>
      <description>INTERNAL / EXTERNAL by Beth Madeley&#xA;https://player.vimeo.com/video/351190550?h=df175dbb06&#xA;INTERNAL / EXTERNAL, by Beth Madeley, is based on the idea of using animation as ‘therapy’ by exploring stream-of-consciousness frame by frame and free-writing to externalize internal feelings left from trauma. In this animation video, I worked very closely with the animator in discussing what she wanted to achieve sonically; however, we did not follow traditional working methods in order to achieve this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanderscapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/wanderscapes-royal-court-theatre-wigan-old-courts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:12:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/wanderscapes-royal-court-theatre-wigan-old-courts/</guid>
      <description>Wanderscapes - Royal Court Theatre – Wigan Old Courts&#xA;Installation piece for the Wanderscapes Project by the Old Courts, Wigan.&#xA;This piece was written as part of the Wanderscapes: Social Resonances sound and music audio walk commissioned by The Old Courts Wigan, released July 2021. The piece contains a mix of samples including cinema projectors, audiences, orchestral instruments and on site construction sounds at the Royal Court alongside original music to represent the history and the development of the building, which is currently in restoration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contractions by Mike Bartlett</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/contractions-by-mike-bartlett/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:47:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/contractions-by-mike-bartlett/</guid>
      <description>Original Music for Whatstick Theatre’s production of Contractions, written by Mike Bartlett. For this production, the music uses a mix of repetitive, minimalist motifs on percussive strings to create movement. The music is semi-inspired by baroque dances, as well as textures and drones inspired by the breath and body, transitioning from rigid, rhythmic music to freer, breathy textures as the play develops. Below is the main theme which is played at the beginning and end of the play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record Player Scores</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/record-player-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:52:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/record-player-scores/</guid>
      <description>Rachael Gibson&#xD;Link will open in a new tab&#xD;· Record Workshop Track 2 by Ray Gibson - Composer&#xD;Link will open in a new tab&#xD;This is one of the sections of an improvisation workshop I ran during my time at Goldsmiths. I asked members of the local community and friends with different levels of knowledge around musical score making to create a new graphic score using different materials, which were to be placed onto a spinning piece of card on a record player.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touch Based Scoring &amp; Improvisation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/touch-based-scoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:19:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/touch-based-scoring/</guid>
      <description>Rachael Gibson&#xD;Link will open in a new tab&#xD;· Touch Objects Workshop Track 1 by Ray Gibson - Composer&#xD;Link will open in a new tab&#xD;An example of the wearable device used for improvisation&#xA;This is one of the sections of an improvisation workshop I ran during my time at Goldsmiths. It features participants with a range of musical backgrounds, from pop musicians, classically trained musicians and those with no musical experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Reach Out Into Darkness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/i-reach-out-into-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:45:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/i-reach-out-into-darkness/</guid>
      <description>I Reach Out Into Darkness is a postcard piece for any pitched solo instrument written for the Illuminate Women’s Music season 1 2020 Online concert.&#xA;This piece aims to shift our focus in music making from using our instruments as a tool for specific sound making within a composition and towards the relationship between our bodies, instruments and what sounds occur when we pay attention to what and how we feel.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
